

www.heiux.com czarnecki.t@outlook.com +48 500 309 303

Work eligibility: EU (Polish citizen) China (family permit)

# Tomasz Czarnecki

## a Product Designer (UX/UI)

with an Intercultural Background

#### **Personal Statement**

A passionate **Product Designer (UX/UI)** and **Developer**, a **Problem Solver** with more than 6 years of overseas working experience.

Excellent **algorithmic thinking** skills and mission to create logical experiences combining user and business needs. Proven track record of intercultural work experience, including project managing roles.

Experienced in designing, introducing and maintaining **design systems**. Always focusing on providing experiences that are profitable and precisely adapted to the target group's needs.

Could contribute to your digital products since the research phase, through prototyping and front-end development. Additionally could help to upgrade existing products by providing heuristic evaluation, analytics, and user testing.

## **Professional Experience**

05.2020 - now

6 months

Product Designer (UX/UI) • macopedia.com • EU-wide

Skills: design systems, problem solving, design thinking, usability testing, prototyping Tools: Figma, Adobe CC, Jira, Odoo, Mattermost

- Standardised company's workflow by introducing a cohesive Design System;
- Transferred design workflow to cloud-based software Figma;
- Organised a series of Figma lectures for co-workers;
- Worked independently with clients across the European Union;
- Encouraged usage of Design Thinking methodology in the company's strategy;

08.2019 - 05.2020

10 months

**Design Consultant • heiux.com • Worldwide** 

Skills: UX process, problem solving, design thinking, usability testing, prototyping Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe CC, Jira, Html, CSS, JavaScript, React

- After leaving the full-time position, worked as a Design Consultant:
- Worked location independently with European and Chinese clients;
- In spare time between project contributed UX Design to Open Source software;
- Expanded knowledge concerning Design Processes and Design Systems;

06.2017 - 07.2019

2 years 1 month

**Project Architect • SEVEN International • Guizhou, China** 

Skills: Chinese, management, leadership, working with tight deadlines, recruiting Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Lumion, Adobe InDesign/Photoshop

- Successfully led team of 10 Chinese-only speaking designers;
- Simultaneously managed teams located on 2 continents: in China and Poland;
- Provided conceptual designs for 4 Social Hosing projects and 5 local Banks;
- Led recruitment processes of 12 junior staff-members (for Polish office);
- Prepared series of Rhinoceros 3D courses (in Chinese office);
- Led client meetings and presentations for Chinese customers;

06.2016 - 06.2017

1 year

Architect • PWD Architecture • Beijing, China

Skills: sketching, research, concept design, working with tight deadlines Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Played a crucial role in winning 21 million m<sup>2</sup> Urban Planning competition;
- Saved hundreds of working hours by building an Urban Planning Library;
- Taught series of Grasshopper workshops for coworkers;
- Introduced parametric design methodology;

04.2015 - 05.2016

Junior Architect • MAD Architects • Beijing, China

1 year 1 month

Skills: parametric design, algorithmic thinking, genetic algorithms, optimisation Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Was the main architect and developer of a Scripting Library;
- Was a key member of the company's Parametric Research Group;
- Saved hundreds of working hours by providing complex parametric models;

08.2014 - 02.2015

7 months

Junior Architect • SEVEN International • Poznan, Poland and Guizhou, China Skills: Chinese, intercultural communication, management, concept design: Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign, AutoCAD

Provided conceptions of buildings that were later realized by Chinese team;

09.2013 - 06.2014

9 months

Construction Site Intern • Budnex Developer • Gorzow, Poland

Helped a construction site manager to supervise the quality of construction;

11.2012 - 02.2013

4 months

**Construction Site Manager/Translator** • Kaja Horeca Interieurs • Netherlands

Provided Polish-English translation on construction sites;

### **Formal Education**

09.2014 - 04.2015

8 months

**Building and Environment Ph.D.** • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

- 2 semesters of Ph.D. studies realized at Faculty of Civil Engineering;
- Focused on Parametric Design: Grasshopper, C#, Algorithmic Thinking;

09.2011 - 06.2012

10 months

**Architecture Erasmus** • Istanbul Technical University • Turkey

· 2 semesters of international exchange;

03.2011 - 06.2014

3 years 4 months

Architecture M.Sc. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• Graduated with the highest A-grade;

09.2007 - 02.2011

3 years 6 months

Architecture B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

Supervisor: prof. Ewa Pruszewicz-Sipińska, dean of the Architecture Faculty;

09.2006 - 06.2007

10 months

Computer Science B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• 2 semesters of B.Eng. studies in English;

#### **Skills and Tools**

skills

- Problem solving
- Prototyping
- Design thinking

- Working under pressure
- Usability testing • Information architecture • User research
- Management • Teamwork

tools

• Figma

- Adobe CC
- React

- Adobe XD
- Git

Javascript

• Jira

- Npm/Node.js
- CSS

• Html

Odoo

Agile

languages

• English: C2

• Polish: Native

• Chinese: B2

## **Courses and Trainings**

**UX Design Masterclass** • by Matt Hryhorsky

Master Digital Product Design: UX Research & UI Design • by Rob Sutcliffe UX Design & User Experience Design Course • by Daniel Walter Scott User Experience Design - Adobe XD UI UX Design • by Daniel Walter Scott Responsive Web Design - HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap • by Daniel Walter Scott UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development • by Joe Natoli The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery • by Andrei Neagoie